{
    "id": "59c872ec8fb74454a9a2a8838aebf187",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We ...................................... for them.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about an action or situation that is going on at the moment of speaking.",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "are waiting",
                "have been waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ...................................... for London tomorrow.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about pre-planned future events. ",
            "answers": [
                "leave",
                "am leaving",
                "would leave"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Wait. I ..................................",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "come",
                "will come",
                "am coming"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ...................................... meeting him at the party.",
            "description": "The verb remember is not normally used in the continuous form.",
            "answers": [
                "remember",
                "am remembering",
                "have remembered"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He ........................................ to a local football club.",
            "description": "The word belong is not normally used in the continuous form.",
            "answers": [
                "belongs",
                "is belonging",
                "has been belonging"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She .......................................... many books.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about finished past events when we do not mention exactly when those actions took place.",
            "answers": [
                "published",
                "has published",
                "publish"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We ................................... all of them.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "invite",
                "inviting",
                "have invited"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Somebody ...................................... the gate unlocked.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about finished past events whose effect is still felt in the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "leaves",
                "is leaving",
                "has left"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ..................................... them for a long time.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to talk about an action that began sometime in the past and is still continuing.",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "have known",
                "have been knowing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ....................................... me several times.",
            "description": "We can use the present perfect tense to talk about a past action when it is not mentioned when the action took place.",
            "answers": [
                "helped",
                "has helped",
                "is helping"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ............................................... the violin for two years.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect continuous to talk about an action that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "is learning",
                "has been learning",
                "learns"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ......................................... it now.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "repent",
                "repents",
                "am repenting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}